<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Studies | Быкасов Владислав Дмитриевич</title>
    <link>https://lunev-cyber.github.io/en/tags/studies/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lunev-cyber.github.io/en/tags/studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Studies</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://lunev-cyber.github.io/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Studies</title>
      <link>https://lunev-cyber.github.io/en/tags/studies/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Week — First Tests and Project Work</title>
      <link>https://lunev-cyber.github.io/en/post/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lunev-cyber.github.io/en/post/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-of-june-2-to-june-8&#34;&gt;📌 Week of June 2 to June 8&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week turned out to be eventful. We took a test in mathematical analysis — the tasks were more challenging than I expected, but the experience was valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In business process practice, we started working on a group project: modeling the business process of an online store. We created a BPMN diagram — it turned out to be more interesting than it sounded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also began exploring SQL — the database homework really made me work hard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Week of Studies — New Impressions and Adaptation</title>
      <link>https://lunev-cyber.github.io/en/post/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lunev-cyber.github.io/en/post/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-of-may-26-to-june-1&#34;&gt;📌 Week of May 26 to June 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week marked the start of a new academic cycle. It was a bit exciting and a little stressful at first because the business informatics subjects seemed quite extensive. What stood out most were the first lectures on information systems — the lecturer shared real-life implementation cases from major companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Practical programming classes began with an introduction to Python basics. I was surprised at how quickly time flies when writing code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of classes, I got to know my classmates — we prepared together for an economics seminar. It feels like a lot of interesting things lie ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
